http://www.almex-online.com/northamerica/en/privacy/

FUSIONCLUBAlmex BrandsCloseALMEXBAT division of Almex GroupEmsys productsFusion SystemsvotechAlmex LightweightAlmex InstituteAlmex Global ServicesOften copied, never duplicated.Open menuOpen menuBrandsCloseBrandsALMEXBAT division of Almex GroupEmsys productsFusion SystemsvotechAlmex LightweightAlmex InstituteAlmex Global ServicesHomeProductsCloseProductsHeavyweight PressesLightweightIndustrial PressesVulcanizing Splice MaterialsCold Bond ProductsBelt RepairLagging & LiningControl SystemsFluid & Pressure PumpsRip DetectionBelt Monitoring & SteeringTire PressesSpecialty EquipmentDust SuppressionBelt Winders & StandsBrakes & ClampsBelt CleaningStandard Hand & Power ToolsIdlers & RollersFlameproof PressesServicesCloseServicesOn-SiteOEM ServicesLab TestingTrainingCloseTraining3-Day Splice SchoolAlmex Institute Certification TrainingOperator TrainingResourcesSpares & RepairsCloseSpares & RepairsRefurbish & RepairSpare PartsAbout UsCloseAbout UsAbout Almex GroupAlmex HistoryCareersContact UsFind EventsPress ReleasesShaw Almex Industries Limited Privacy PolicyThe Almex Commitment to PrivacyThis Privacy Policy covers how Shaw Almex Industries Limited (“Almex”) collects, uses and discloses personal information in connection with its provision of various computer related and technical consulting services, as well as how we treat information received via this website. Almex is committed to ensuring that all personal information obtained by or provided to us is handled securely, conscientiously and in accordance with applicable privacy law, including Canada’s Personal Information Protection and Electronic Documents Act (“PIPEDA”).
As part of our responsible information handling practices, Almex has developed this Privacy Policy in order to keep you informed of the ways in which we collect, use and disclose personal information. This Privacy Policy may be revised from time to time to reflect our evolving business and the nature of the products and services we offer to you. To ensure that you are aware of our current privacy practices, we recommend that you review this statement periodically. Should you choose to provide us with your personal information, we will refer you to this Privacy Policy at the time your information is collected, whether in writing, over the telephone or online. You will be deemed to have agreed with the terms and conditions contained in this statement upon providing us with your personal information.
Personal Information“Personal information” means any information that can be used to specifically identify you, such as your name, residential telephone number, address and email address and includes information about your product and service purchases and usage, credit information and billing records, as well as any service requests or recorded complaints made by you.
Personal information is collected by Almex only when you knowingly choose to provide it us, such as when you inquire about our products or services. We may also receive personal information from our business partners and other third parties provided that such third parties confirm to us that they have obtained your consent to the disclosure of your personal information. Almex needs to collect certain types of personal information from you in order to provide you with products and services that you request or for purposes otherwise described in this Privacy Policy. Should you decline to provide such information, Almex may not be able to provide you with certain products or services.
Additionally, Almex may from time to time be provided with personal information collected by our corporate clients for the purposes of providing various consulting services requested by our clients. Such services may include the evaluation and analysis of data for the purposes of development of policies, programs and procedures for use by our clients in connection with their internal administration.
Business telephone numbers and addresses, as well as anonymous information, aggregated data, publicly available information, or public directory listing of your name, address, telephone number and electronic address, are not considered personal information.
Collection, Use and ConsentAlmex collects and uses personal information primarily in connection the following commercial activities:
To provide you with the products and services you have requested from us;To establish and maintain commercial relationships with our clients, suppliers and partners, including the administration of customer accounts;To allow us to comply with any requirements imposed upon us by various legal and regulatory boards or agencies;
For recruiting purposes, to allow us to evaluate potential candidates for employment and collect information such as resumes, reference and background information, letters of referral and education documentation.
Almex will only collect items of personal information required for the specific purposes necessary to facilitate your requests or as otherwise identified to you in this Privacy Policy or at the time of collection. Your personal information will not be used for any other purpose without your consent.
Marketing and Promotional PurposesIf you have indicated to Almex that you are interested in receiving offers or information from selected sponsors or advertisers, your personal information would also be used to contact you or to send you e-mail materials and other mailings about products and services that might be of interest to you. You always have the option, however, to withdraw your consent to this use of your personal information or require that Almex excludes you from offers for or information about other products or services.
We will seek your prior consent to the collection, use and disclosure of the information as required by applicable privacy legislation. Subject to legal and contractual requirements, you can refuse to consent to our collection, use or disclosure of information about you. You may also withdraw your consent to any further collection, use or disclosure of information about you at any time by giving us reasonable notice; however, we may not be able to provide you with certain products or services without use of your personal information. If our intended disclosures or uses of personal information change, we will notify you accordingly.
Disclosure of Personal InformationOur employees are familiar with the contents of this Privacy Policy and are informed about our policies and procedures for protecting personal information. Your personal information is only disclosed to those within Almex-owned or affiliated companies with a need to know, which individuals are held accountable for maintaining the confidentiality of all personal information to which they have access.
To ensure that you benefit from our full range of products and services, we may, with your consent, share your personal information, amongst Almex’s trusted partners. Any such third parties will only use your personal information to provide you with the products and services you have requested through Almex and will be given only the information necessary for carrying out their services in this regard.
SecurityAlmex has established safeguarding measures to uphold the security of personal information provided to us, regardless of the format in which it is held. We have instituted policies and procedures to protect against the unauthorized use, access, disclosure, destruction, loss or theft of any Personal Information. All electronically-stored or transmitted personal information resides on secure servers behind a firewall and database access is carefully monitored and restricted. All information stored in hard copy format is also access-limited and securely maintained.
AccuracyAlmex takes reasonable steps to ensure that personal information we hold about you is accurate, complete and up-to-date. However, please inform us of any change of name, address or other information. In the event you have questions about the accuracy of factual information we have collected about you, you will have access to that information in order to verify and update it. If we have disclosed inaccurate information about you to a third party, we will be pleased to contact the third party in order to correct the information.
AccessIf you have any questions about the collection, use or disclosure of your personal information, you may contact our Chief Privacy Officer using the contact information provided below:
Shaw Almex Industries323 Glover RoadStoney Creek, ON L8E 5M3CanadaAttention: Chief Privacy OfficerEmail: sail@almex.comFax: (905) 315-9679
Except in limited circumstances, Almex will disclose to you type of information we hold about you, allow you access to your personal information and provide an account of the use that has been made or is being made of the information, including the third parties to which it has been disclosed.Almex will only decline an access request in those circumstances permitted or required by applicable privacy legislation. If Almex refuses access to you, it will provide you with the reasons for its refusal upon request. Exceptions may include information that contains references to other individuals, information that cannot be disclosed for legal, security or commercial proprietary reasons, and information that is subject to solicitor-client or litigation privilege.
Our WebsitesWhen you visit the Almex websites (i.e. www.almex.com, www.fusionclubpoints.com ), our servers log non-identifiable, anonymous and aggregate data gleaned from your computer’s web browser and IP information. This information may include your Internet address, the address of the website you are coming from, your browser language setting, your geographical location, the amount of time you spend visiting our website, and if you link to us through a search engine, the keywords you used to locate us. We may this information to analyze trends, administer the site, track the movement of our users, and gather broad demographic information for aggregate use. Almex never uses this information to identify specific individuals.Our websites contain contact forms, email links (job postings and general inquiries) and account login that gather personal information that enable us to respond to your query. Submitting the forms with the fields filled is implied as consent to sharing that information.
We may use cookies on the Almex websites “Cookies” are small pieces of information that a website sends to your device while you are viewing a website.
Among other things, cookies allow us to provide you with a more personal and interactive experience and to improve our marketing efforts.
If you choose to disable cookies some areas or features of our websites may not work properly.
For mobile users, Almex may collect information from your mobile device such as unique identifying information broadcast from your device or hardware and software specifications.LinksWhile our websites may contain links to other sites that may be of interest to our users, please be aware that Almex is not responsible for the privacy practices of such other sites. We encourage our users to be aware that when they leave our website we accept no liability for the subsequent treatment of their personal information by any third party. Any information provided to such third parties is not administered by this Privacy Policy, nor is the responsibility of Almex. We advise our users to carefully review the privacy policies of each and every website that collects personally identifiable information.
Notification of ChangesIf we decide to change this Privacy Policy, we will prominently post those changes on our websites so our users are always aware of what information we collect, how we use it, and under what circumstances, if any, we disclose it.
If at any point we decide to use personally identifiable information in a manner different from that stated at the time it was collected, we will notify users by way of an email or by a prominent notice on our website. Users will have a choice as to whether or not we use their information in this different manner. We will use information in accordance with the version of the Privacy Policy under which the information was collected.
Change in OwnershipIn the event that Almex or any of its assets are acquired by a third party, personal information acquired by Almex may be one of the assets transferred.
Contact UsUpon request, Almex will be pleased to provide additional information about this Privacy Policy and its administration in order that you have a better understanding of our personal information handling practices. Please direct any inquiries in respect of this Privacy Policy to our Chief Privacy Officer, at any of the coordinates set forth earlier in this policy.
If for any reason you are dissatisfied with the outcome of any inquiry made of our Chief Privacy Officer, we suggest that you contact the Privacy Commissioner of Canada by calling 1-800-282-1376 or by writing to:
Office of the Privacy Commissioner of Canada112 Kent StreetOttawa, ON K1A 1H3
Or visit www.priv.gc.ca.ALMEXBAT division of Almex GroupEmsys productsFusion SystemsvotechAlmex LightweightAlmex InstituteAlmex Global Services© 2020 Shaw Almex Industries Ltd.About AlmexContactPrivacyCareers2020 All Rights Reserved.
